Guide to the Myrick Freeman Papers, 1967-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1967-2000, (2 boxes)
  - Reviews
    - Review of Air/Water Pollution Report, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Review of Economic Valuation with Stated Preferences: A Manual, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Review of EPA Approach to Assessing Non-Cancer Health Effects from Formaldehyde and Benefits from Reducing Non-Cancer Health Effects as a Result of Implementing Formaldehyde Emission Limits for Composite Wood Products, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Review of Economics and Statistics: Land Prices Substantially Underestimate the Value of Environmental Quality: A Comment, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Review of Schulze, et al. and Charles W. Howe, Natural Resrouce Economics, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Review of Gardner & Brown, Economic Valuation of Shoreline: A Comment, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Public Finance: Mixed Goods and Option Demand-A Comment, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Review of Research Capacity-Building Proposal from the South Asian Network of Development and Environmental Economics (SANDEE), 2006 (Box 4)
    - Review of P.O. Johansson: Cost-Benefit Analysis of Environmental Change, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Review of Dieter Helm, Ed., Managing the Environment: Economic Policy Towards the Environment, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Review of David W. Pearce and R. Kerry Turner, Economics of Natural Resources and the Environment, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Journal of Environmental Economics and Management: Review of Factorial Survey Methods and Willingness to Pay: A Response to Goodman by Freeman, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Journal of Environmental Economics and Management: Response to Henry M. Peskin's One More Externality Article-Comments, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Review of A Comparison of Alternative Approaches for Estimating Recreation and Related Benefits of Water Quality Improvements, 1982 (Box 4)
    - The Universities Council on Water Resources: The Clean Water Act: An Economist's Appraisal, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Review of Beach Nourishment and Protection -Sand Against the Sea, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Intellect: Review of M.W. Jones-Lee, The Value of Life: An Economic Analysis, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Review and Critique of FERC's Benefit-Cost Analysis for the Edwards Dam Project, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Natural Resources Journal: Review of Thomas M. Power's The Economic Value of the Quality of Life, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Review of Preliminary Cost-Benefit Analysis of Scrap Metal Raditation Standards, 1997 (Box 4)
- Research, 1967-2010, (Less than 1 box)
  The Research series contains notes, research articles and papers, transparencies, and other materials which Freeman collected or produced in preparation for various research and consulting projects.
  - Wells Harbor, 1997 (Box 4)
  - ENRAP Transparencies, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Basin Mills Slides (Box 4)
  - Massachussetts Landfill Case, 1990 (Box 4)
  - NAS - PCB's Controls & Costs (Box 4)
  - Ellis/Fisher CRAB Model Benefits (Box 4)
  - Council on Environmental Quality Clean Air (Box 4)
- Electronic Records, 1990-2004, (12 DVDs)
  The Electronic Records series contains DVDs with files for Freeman's papers, teaching, correspondence, and workshop participation.
  [Electronic records have been migrated to a library server. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Environmental Economics Program for South East Asia: Correspondence & Teaching, 1998-2004 (Box 4)
  - Bowdoin College: Correspondence & Other Documents, 1997-2000 (Box 4)
  - Teaching Environmental Studies and Economics, 1995-2000 (Box 4)
  - Consulting Projects: 1990's (Box 4)
  - Consulting Projects: 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)'s Science Advisory Board, 1994-2006 (Box 4)
  - Bowdoin College: Valuing Nature Workshop: 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1988-1995 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1990-2003 (Box 4)
  - Chapters Contributed to Books, c. 1999-2003 (Box 4)
  - New York State Externalities Costing Project, 1993-1997 (Box 4)
  - EPA Research Project on Values of Marine Recreational Activities (Box 4)